Three rings for the Elven-kings under the sky
Seven for the Dwarf-lords in their halls of stone
Nine for mortal men doomed to die
KEEPERS (Fellowship)
A fantasy based on the novel by JRR Tolkien
Part 1
One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne
In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie.
One Ring to rule them all, One Ring to find them,
One Ring to bring them all and in the darkness bind them.
In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie.”
Our story is largely concerned with Hobbits
We'll get familiar with their lifestyle and customs
Hobbits are not famous, but they're are a very ancient people.
They love quietness and peace,
ripe grains and green pastures.
But now the world is too small and busy
So they live in their own world.
The world that is called Shire.
They're small but sturdy
In the days of peace and prosperity
They live as they like
- and they surely like fun.
Hobbits aren't warlike and never fought each other
Maybe they love earthly goods so much
because in the times of hardship they used to get without them
(which is hard to believe looking at their funny faces)
Now Hobbits are preparing for a party:
Bilbo Baggins is 111 today.
Yes, yes, you heard it right: 111 years.
Hobbits had long lives
Even in his 111 Bilbo looks like he's 50, no more
- when there's no greediness and evil in one's soul
the body stays young longer
— My dear friends! I'm so glad to see you here, at my party!
Here're the Bulgers! here's Peregrine Took!
Merry Brandybuck!
And you, my cousin, my dear Lobelia!
Glad to see you here!
- Bilbo! You're too spendthrift! How much did you spend on the food? Bilbo!…
- This is Lobelia Sackville-Baggins! She's always the same!
Lobelia, stop caring so much about my money-sack contents!
Just think! 111 years! A magic number! Three "1"-s!
Today is an important day! But we'll talk about it later…
- You've wasted your estate! What's left for us, your relatives, after your de…your party.
— Did you mean "after my death"?
- No!
- Lobelia! It's my birthday! You'll die waiting!
- I meant "your party"! I meant "your party"!
- (laughter) She meant "your party"!
- OK, OK, "my party"!
- Smile, smile, Lobelia! You'll look as if you were 80-85, no more!
- Ah, Gandalf! Our great mage and wizard! My dear! I know you for a century!
I'm so glad to see you!
Yes, dear friend, long time no see! Here's my gift to you!
- Dear friends! Welcome to the table! Help yourself!
- So, have you decided?
- I need a rest. Long rest. I told you before.
I'll never come back here. And I've no reasons for that. I've done everything.
I got old, Gandalf, very old.
- I think your decision is right, Bilbo.
- Yes, I've decided. I'll leave everything to my nephew Frodo.
He's 33 now, an adulthood for hobbits…
I hope, you'll keep an eye on him?
- With both my eyes, rest assured!
- Here, please give this envelope to him, it has all the instructions.
I leave him everything.
- Everything?
- Everything!
- And the Ring too?
- The Ring? Where's…? No, not the Ring.
- So where is it?
- Here, but I won't leave it… my precious.
- Bilbo! I think you should leave it! Or maybe you don't want?
- Why do you care so much for this ring? Do you want it for yourself?
No, Gandalf, I won't give away my precious.
- Yes, Bilbo! "My precious"! Gollum, its previous owner, also called it so!
Come one, bring it here! I'm not going to take it.
- Gandalf! I won't give up the Ring! I won't give up!
- Forgive me, Gandalf! Something happened to me… I'm better now.
You know, I feel like someone's eye constantly looks for me…
I got so thin, like butter on a miser's bread!
I know… it's the Ring… It's draining me and subjugating me!
- Reject, reject the RIng, Bilbo!
- All right, Gandalf. I'll leave the Ring to Frodo.
I need to say good bye to everyone.
- Dear friends! My fellow hobbits! I, Bilbo Baggins, address you!
My precious Tooks and Brandybucks! Boffins and Goodbodies!
I hope you have as much fun as I!
- We do!
- I'm very glad!
- Bilbo! Live 300 years!
- Fellows, 300 is a bit too much, I won't promise that!
- Are you happy on my birthday?
- Yes!
- I'm very glad!
but today's there's another birthday: the birthday of my nephew Frodo!
He's 33 today! He'd achieved full age and he's now my heir.
With a regret I'd like to say that, while living with you is a pleasure, but I had to say good bye, fellow Hobbits…
- Why are joking like this?
- I depart!
- You forgot to put down something, Bilbo!
- Excuse me, Gandalf
- Why did he leave all his estate to this milksucker, Frodo? We the Sackville-Bagginses are the closest kin!
- This oaf Bilbo ran away again! No rest for the old fool! But that's nothing — the food is still on the table, right?
- Bilbo departed, right?
- Yes, he's gone.
- I was hoping it's a joke for whole day. Although, in my soul I knew — he always joked in earnest.
- Don't worry. He'll be all right.
- He left something for you. You're now the master of the whole estate, the whole Bag End
- Lord, will I never see him again?
- This envelope holds a golden ring.
- Why, the Ring too? He even left it to me? I wonder, why? But it may come useful…
- Yes, it may, or may not. If I was you, I'd not touch it. It's dangerous.
…Its evil power is so great, it will break any mortal. The bearer of the Ring doesn't die but doesn't really live either. He just tugs his life, without joy and with great hardship.
- Horrible! But it looks so beautiful…
- Beware! He who wears the Ring often becomes transparent, only visible to the Dark Lord, becomes a servant to the Dark forces..
- Gandalf! Who is the Lord of the Rings?
- The Dark Lord reigns over the Dark forces that make all the evil in the world. He lives in the terrible land of Mordor.
The darkness changes it shapes, grows and wants to devour the whole world.
- I hope I'll never see it myself.
- We can't choose our own fate.
We have little time, Frodo.
- Why had this accursed Ring to get into our Bilbo's hands?
- Here's why:
- On the coasts of the great river Anduin there lived people very similar to Hobbits.
One beautiful morning, two friends, Deagol and Smeagol, went fishing.
- A bite! Hey, a bite! Aaah…
- Look what I found!
- A ring!
- Yes, a little ring!
- Give it to me, dear Deagol!
- Why should I?
- It's my birthday! I'd like it as a gift!
- I gave you a gift this morning. This ring I'll leave to myself!…
- But how, my dear, but why? How can you, dear Deagol?
- You were wrong, my dear… You were wrong… You were wrong, my dear…
- The Ring was so wondrous, so shiny… Smeagol put it on his finger — and disappeared!
He figured that the Ring makes him invisible.
He wore it more and more often, sneaking, eavesdropping and pranking, until his kin banished him.
This made him even more evil and turned him into a real monster.
…he grumbled like this all the time, so others started to call him "Gollum".
- Tell me, Gandalf, how did you learn about the Ring and Gollum? Maybe you're making it all up?
- Some things I knew before, and some I learned. I saw Gollum!
- Now spit it out: where did you get the Ring?
- This is my ring, my precious! I inherited it from my grandma!
- From grandma? You're lying, lad! Your grandma was practical, sure, but I don't think her household kept the Rings of Power!
And she wouldn't give them to a villain you are.
- She had a lot of trinkets!
Gollum dropped the Ring in a cave; this is where our Bilbo found it. Now it's yours, my boy.
- What else had he told you?
- I'd threatened him with fire, and he told me the real story. I learned how he lost the Ring…
After that he all petrified and just whined, as if some horror had chained his tongue.
But he also hinted that he found some wonderful friends and they'll teach everyone a lesson in Orcish.
- "Orcish"? Horror, what's "Orcs"?
- They are Hobbits' enemies. You'll learn it later.
It looked like he already was brought to the Dark Lord in Mordor, and the Enemy pulled out of him, where the Ring of Power is, and that you hold it.
…Your sweet Shire is in danger.
- No, no!… You know what? Gandalf, I've an idea: let's destroy the Ring now! We'll throw it in the fireplace!
- No. The ring was forged deep in the mount Orodruin and can be destroyed only there - if you really want to make it disappear.
- Gandalf, your story is so long that I got hungry again.
- Yes, you'd better have a meal before a long trip.
- What trip?
- You're not a simple Hobbit, Frodo. You're a chosen one.
- "a chosen one"?
- …and great trials await you.
Look, there's an inscription inside the Ring.
…Nine for mortal men doomed to die
- You'll be hunted by nine Black Riders, servants of the Darkness. They'll put obstacles on your way.
- Nine Black Riders… Obstacles…  But surely you'll help me!
- No… I'm a Wizard. And only a simple Hobbit can destroy the Ring. You, Frodo.
- I? Alone?
- You won't be alone. Your friends will join you!
- My friends!
- Yes! Jolly Merry Brandybuck, caring Sam Gamgee, strong as a bull Peregrin Took.
- Well, my friends! Let's go!
- But wait… you need to change name. You were Frodo Baggins, now you'll be called Frodo Underhill.
- Underhill…
- And one more thing. Once you leave you'll meet your first trial: the winter will come.
- Gandalf! How come? I'm afraid of cold, it's always summer in Shire… I won't go anywhere!
- Yes it's always summer in Shire, but the road goes through winter. Onwards, Frodo!
- Onwards it is then…
Here's how the long travel from Shire to Mordor started.
The raindrops sang their song, then first snowflake came.
The Gandalf's prophecy came true: the winter has come.
The song was merry some time and sad another time.
You know, when you're wet and your baggage weight tripled, and then frost bites, the thoughts aren't so merry.
…and then one day they heard the sound hooves knocking!
It came from afar, they couldn't see the source, but understood it's a danger.
- Hey! Someone's riding! Boys!
- Come here, everyone!
- We need to hide behind a hill!
- Why should we hide?
- Quiet! Hide, everyone, quickly!
- We need to be very cautious!
- Oh Frodo, what a horror.
- Poor us! When we have a chance for a breakfast, lunch and a dinner?
- I'm hungry indeed!
- Our road goes to the Buckland, to the old Maggot's tavern. Maggot will help us!
- Let's go, boys!
- Here you are! What do you want?
- We need some warmth and food!
- The tavern is opened to everyone!
Eat and drink, just pay the money!
- Thank you, the beer is delicious! And the pastries are exceptional.
- Do you like it? All right, spill it out, who are you?
Actually, I know that myself. Who in the Shire doesn't know Frodo Baggins and his good fellows?
- Mister, I'm not Frodo Baggins. My name is Underhill.
- Why would you change the name? But I've a guess
- What could you guess? Our travel is a secret. We only need to get to the ferry…
- Gotcha! I must warn you! Although maybe you don't need it…
- We need it! Master! Speak!
- Three days ago I heard my dogs barking furiously. There was a scary rider knocking on my gate.
- What a horror!
- All clad in black, on black horse.
- What was next?
- He kept asking if I know where Frodo from the Bag End and the three friends of him had gone. "Tell me where, I'll bring you gold!"
… he was so scary: hissed, growled,  bowed to the ground, as if he wasn't alive…
- And what did you say?
- And I was all like: Get out of here, bring your gold to someone else, I know nothing!
- Quiet, quiet! So, you don't need gold, but keep asking money from us, eh?
0 165
- Of course, you gotta pay for the drinks, but for betrayal… I don't need money for betrayal, I'm an honest person!
My life isn't easy but I never betrayed anyone!
But about you — I know something. The folks are talking!
- What?
- You're good lads! Never did evil to anyone! Go back home, live quietly!…
- You see, we never did evil. My word! And will never do to anyone.
But I have to ask for a favor: help us to get to the river ferry. Be a lad!
- Do you have coin for that? Ah, just kidding!
I'll ask my brothers to bring you there safely.
Hurry up! The night is coming.
- My dear, my good Hobbits! I thought it well, and I decided: our travel is vey dangerous.
It's nothing like a quest for a treasure, not a "trip there and back again".
The death awaits at every corner!
- Ah, Frodo, like we'd never guessed! We only follow this Ring because we know how dangerous the road is.
We go to help you!
- "The Ring"? You said "the Ring", Merry? How do you know?
- Did you think we don't know? I knew about the Ring for like, 100 years. Bilbo himself told me.
You wanted to be secretive, so I didn't chatter…
- I know about the Ring too. By accident…
-… And so when Gandalf asked us to help you, we said nothing against!
- Remember, he told you: "Take those you can trust".
- Who can I trust now? With friends like this…
- We'll go into fire, and water, and snow for you!
- We won't abandon you, don't even think about it! We're your friends!
- Thanks, friends!
- Frodo, we follow you with full understanding, don't worry!
The road went uphill. Tree branches were getting denser and darker. The silence was eerie.
But Hobbits felt like they were being watched by cold, suspicious, hostile eyes.
- Where's the winter?
- It probably ended… or suspended
- Ouch, friends! Looks like we're in the Old Forest.
- They tell scary stories about unholy things here…
- Enough, Pippin, I don't believe int this fairytales… but they say the trees in this forest don't like strangers… and they watch…watch with all their…
- Leaves? They don't have eyes, don't they?
- Got scared?
- A bit…
- And you, Brandybuck?
- No, and you?
- And Pippin got scared!
- Anyway, we had to go through the Old Forest. There's no other road. No way to avoid the Old Forest.
- Let me throught! Let me through! I plan no malice!
- Quiet, don't cry! It won't help. We're going to die together…
- We won't die, where did you get that? Neither together nor by ourselves.
- I feel drowsy… I'm falling asleep…
- Frodo, don't sleep!
- Why?
- It's not a mere sleep!
- It's a sleep!
- It's some kind of sorcery!
- No, Brandybuck…
- I'm falling asleep too…
- I'm falling asleep too…I'm falling asleep too…
- It's me, eternal Old Man Willow, casting an eternal sleep on you!
Enjoy it! Let all your troubles go.
…Your bodies will weaken, and you'll be a food for the trees of the Old Forest!
Stay here! Eternal sleep! This is what every conscientious person should strive for!
- Whose are these feet? Ah, Brandybuck! Merry! What happened to you?
Pippin! Sam! Wake up, lads, we're in trouble!
- What happened?
- Brandybuck got caught! The Willow swallowed him! Help me!
- Ah you, unholy thing! Wait a bit, I'll bring some fire and we'll burn its skin. Maybe then it'll let our Merry go!
- Sam, help me! Merry, do you hear us?
- Here, let me put fire on it. Here, get it! How are you, Merry?
- Stop it! Stop it! Or this thing will cut me in half!
- Remove the fire!… Quiet! I here a song!
A song! The help is near! Boys, follow me!
- Whoa! Whoa! steady there! Now, my little fellows,
Where be you a-going to, puffing like a bellows?
What's the matter here then?
Do you know who I am?
I'm Tom Bombadil!
Tell me what's your trouble!`
- Sir! My friend is caught in the willow-tree!
- What? Old Man Willow? Naught worse than that, eh? That can soon be mended. I know the tune for him.
You let him out again, Old Man Willow! What be you a-thinking of? You shouldn't be waking!
Eat earth, Dig deep! Drink water! Bombadil is talking!
- One! Two! Three!
- Thank you sir!
- You shall come home with me! The table is laden with yellow cream, honeycomb, and white bread and butter. Golderry is waiting.
- He speaks in poems!
- Who's this Goldberry?
- Maybe his wife?
- Time enough for questions around the supper table.
You follow after me a quick as you are able!
- Don't worry, dear friends. No danger will find you here. Leave the damp night in the forest!
Maybe you're still afraid of the fogs, dark trees, swamps and sloughs? Forget it! No fears! Now you're safe with Tom Bombadil!
- Here's my pretty lady! Here's my Goldberry clothed all in silver-green with flowers in her girdle!
Is the table laden? I see yellow cream and honeycomb, and white bread, and butter,
milk, cheese and green herbs and ripe berries gathered. Is that enough for us? Is the supper ready?
- Let's eat, lads!
- Wash yourself first! Warm clean water is the best way to leave the fears behind!
- Now it's time for the supper.
- Eat boys, eat!
- Time to sleep. The night will fly quickly, and you'll be ready to continue your travel.
- Sleep… Sleep… Sleep…
- Who are you, the giant? Tell me!
- Don't you know my name, Tom? That's the only answer.
- And I am Frodo!
- Restore your strength and fear nothing. I know everything about you, no need to tell. I'm glad I can help you on your long path.
- Thank you!
- Show me your magic ring.
- The Ring? Well, I can even give it up to you…
- No, no, just show it to me.
- Here, take it from me, it's scary…
- There're forces stronger than this Ring. The force of fearlessness and love for life will damage it… But only you can destroy it once and for all.
- We?
- Yes. Take it back.
Tomorrow, new trials await you. Be prepared for everything. Go the western slope of the Downs, besides the Barrows.
…If you're lucky, you'll strike the Great Road in a day's journey.
- …The Great Road…
- Listen carefully and remember:
Ho! Tom Bombadil, Tom Bombadillo!
By water, wood and hill, by the reed and willow,
By fire, sun and moon, harken now and hear us!
Come, Tom Bombadil, for our need is near us!
- This is in case you're in trouble.
- …in case we're in trouble…
- Now sleep!
- Good night!
- Frodo, my friend! Now you're safe with your friends. But remember, this is just a respite.
New dangers await for you. The winter will return.
- Wake up, friends! Get up!
Speed now! And hold to your purpose!
North with the wind in the left eye and a blessing on your footsteps.
Farewell! Happy travels!
- Looks like I'm lost.
Merry! Sam! Pippin! Where're you, boys?
- FRODO! FRODO!
- Lord, I'm scared!
END OF PART 11
Three rings for the Elven-kings under the sky
Seven for the Dwarf-lords in their halls of stone
Nine for mortal men doomed to die
KEEPERS (Fellowship)
A fantasy based on the novel by JRR Tolkien
Part 1
One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne
In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie.
One Ring to rule them all, One Ring to find them,
One Ring to bring them all and in the darkness bind them.
In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie.”
Our story is largely concerned with Hobbits
We'll get familiar with their lifestyle and customs
Hobbits are not famous, but they're are a very ancient people.
They love quietness and peace,
ripe grains and green pastures.
But now the world is too small and busy
So they live in their own world.
The world that is called Shire.
They're small but sturdy
In the days of peace and prosperity
They live as they like
- and they surely like fun.
Hobbits aren't warlike and never fought each other
Maybe they love earthly goods so much
because in the times of hardship they used to get without them
(which is hard to believe looking at their funny faces)
Now Hobbits are preparing for a party:
Bilbo Baggins is 111 today.
Yes, yes, you heard it right: 111 years.
Hobbits had long lives
Even in his 111 Bilbo looks like he's 50, no more
- when there's no greediness and evil in one's soul
the body stays young longer
— My dear friends! I'm so glad to see you here, at my party!
Here're the Bulgers! here's Peregrine Took!
Merry Brandybuck!
And you, my cousin, my dear Lobelia!
Glad to see you here!
- Bilbo! You're too spendthrift! How much did you spend on the food? Bilbo!…
- This is Lobelia Sackville-Baggins! She's always the same!
Lobelia, stop caring so much about my money-sack contents!
Just think! 111 years! A magic number! Three "1"-s!
Today is an important day! But we'll talk about it later…
- You've wasted your estate! What's left for us, your relatives, after your de…your party.
— Did you mean "after my death"?
- No!
- Lobelia! It's my birthday! You'll die waiting!
- I meant "your party"! I meant "your party"!
- (laughter) She meant "your party"!
- OK, OK, "my party"!
- Ah, Gandalf! Our great mage and wizard! My dear! I know you for a century!
I'm so glad to see you!
Yes, dear friend, long time no see! Here's my gift to you!
- Dear friends! Welcome to the table! Help yourself!
- So, have you decided?
- I need a rest. Long rest. I told you before.
I'll never come back here. And I've no reasons for that. I've done everything.
I got old, Gandalf, very old.
- I think your decision is right, Bilbo.
- Yes, I've decided. I'll leave everything to my nephew Frodo.
He's 33 now, an adulthood for hobbits…
I hope, you'll keep an eye on him?
- With both my eyes, rest assured!
- Here, please give this envelope to him, it has all the instructions.
I leave him everything.
- Everything?
- Everything!
- And the Ring too?
- The Ring? Where's…? No, not the Ring.
- So where is it?
- Here, but I won't leave it… my precious.
- Bilbo! I think you should leave it! Or maybe you don't want?
- Why do you care so much for this ring? Do you want it for yourself?
No, Gandalf, I won't give away my precious.
- Yes, Bilbo! "My precious"! Gollum, its previous owner, also called it so!
Come one, bring it here! I'm not going to take it.
- Gandalf! I won't give up the Ring! I won't give up!
- Forgive me, Gandalf! Something happened to me… I'm better now.
You know, I feel like someone's eye constantly looks for me…
I got so thin, like butter on a miser's bread!
I know… it's the Ring… It's draining me and subjugating me!
- Reject, reject the RIng, Bilbo!
- All right, Gandalf. I'll leave the Ring to Frodo.
I need to say good bye to everyone.
- Dear friends! My fellow hobbits! I, Bilbo Baggins, address you!
My precious Tooks and Brandybucks! Bolgers and Fatbellies!
I hope you have as much fun as I!
- We do!
- I'm very glad!
- Bilbo! Live 300 years!
- Fellows, 300 is a bit too much, I won't promise that!
- Are you happy on my birthday?
- Yes!
- I'm very glad!
but today's there's another birthday: the birthday of my nephew Frodo!
He's 33 today! He'd achieved full age and he's now my heir.
With a regret I'd like to say that, while living with you is a pleasure, but I had to say good bye, fellow Hobbits…
- Why are joking like this?
- I depart!
- You forgot to put down something, Bilbo!
- Excuse me, Gandalf
- Why did he leave all his estate to this milksucker, Frodo? We the Sackville-Bagginses are the closest kin!
- This oaf Bilbo ran away again! No rest for the old fool! But that's nothing — the food is still on the table, right?
- Bilbo departed, right?
- Yes, he's gone.
- I was hoping it's a joke for whole day. Although, in my soul I knew — he always joked in earnest.
- Don't worry. He'll be all right.
- He left something for you. You're now the master of the whole estate, the whole Bag End
- Lord, will I never see him again?
- This envelope holds a golden ring.
- Why, the Ring too? He even left it to me? I wonder, why? But it may come useful…
- Yes, it may, or may not. If I was you, I'd not touch it. It's dangerous.
…Its evil power is so great, it will break any mortal. The bearer of the Ring doesn't die but doesn't really live either. He just tugs his life, without joy and with great hardship.
- Horrible! But it looks so beautiful…
- Beware! He who wears the Ring often becomes transparent, only visible to the Dark Lord, becomes a servant to the Dark forces..
- Gandalf! Who is the Lord of the Rings?
- The Dark Lord reigns over the Dark forces that make all the evil in the world. He lives in the terrible land of Mordor.
The darkness changes it shapes, grows and wants to devour the whole world.
- I hope I'll never see it myself.
- We can't choose our own fate.
We have little time, Frodo.
- Why had this accursed Ring to get into our Bilbo's hands?
- Here's why:
- On the coasts of the great river Anduin there lived people very similar to Hobbits.
One beautiful morning, two friends, Deagol and Smeagol, went fishing.
- A bite! Hey, a bite! Aaah…
- Look what I found!
- A ring!
- Yes, a little ring!
- Give it to me, dear Deagol!
- Why should I?
- It's my birthday! I'd like it as a gift!
- I gave you a gift this morning. This ring I'll leave to myself!…
- But how, my dear, but why? How can you, dear Deagol?
- You were wrong, my dear… You were wrong… You were wrong, my dear…
- The Ring was so wondrous, so shiny… Smeagol put it on his finger — and disappeared!
He figured that the Ring makes him invisible.
He wore it more and more often, sneaking, eavesdropping and pranking, until his kin banished him.
This made him even more evil and turned him into a real monster.
…he grumbled like this all the time, so others started to call him "Gollum".
- Tell me, Gandalf, how did you learn about the Ring and Gollum? Maybe you're making it all up?
- Some things I knew before, and some I learned. I saw Gollum!
- Now spit it out: where did you get the Ring?
- This is my ring, my precious! I inherited it from my grandma!
- From grandma? You're lying, lad! Your grandma was practical, sure, but I don't think her household kept the Rings of Power!
And she wouldn't give them to a villain you are.
- She had a lot of trinkets!
Gollum dropped the Ring in a cave; this is where our Bilbo found it. Now it's yours, my boy.
- What else had he told you?
- I'd threatened him with fire, and he told me the real story. I learned how he lost the Ring…
After that he all petrified and just whined, as if some horror had chained his tongue.
But he also hinted that he found some wonderful friends and they'll teach everyone a lesson in Orcish.
- "Orcish"? Horror, what's "Orcs"?
- They are Hobbits' enemies. You'll learn it later.
It looked like he already was brought to the Dark Lord in Mordor, and the Enemy pulled out of him, where the Ring of Power is, and that you hold it.
…Your sweet Shire is in danger.
- No, no!… You know what? Gandalf, I've an idea: let's destroy the Ring now! We'll throw it in the fireplace!
- No. The ring was forged deep in the mount Orodruin and can be destroyed only there - if you really want to make it disappear.
- Gandalf, your story is so long that I got hungry again.
- Yes, you'd better have a meal before a long trip.
- What trip?
- You're not a simple Hobbit, Frodo. You're a chosen one.
- "a chosen one"?
- …and great trials await you.
Look, there's an inscription inside the Ring.
…Nine for mortal men doomed to die
- You'll be hunted by nine Black Riders, servants of the Darkness. They'll put obstacles on your way.
- Nine Black Riders… Obstacles…  But surely you'll help me!
- No… I'm a Wizard. And only a simple Hobbit can destroy the Ring. You, Frodo.
- I? Alone?
- You won't be alone. Your friends will join you!
- My friends!
- Yes! Jolly Merry Brandybuck, caring Sam Gamgee, strong as a bull Peregrin Took.
- Well, my friends! Let's go!
- But wait… you need to change name. You were Frodo Baggins, now you'll be called Frodo Underhill.
- Underhill…
- And one more thing. Once you leave you'll meet your first trial: the winter will come.
- Gandalf! How come? I'm afraid of cold, it's always summer in Shire… I won't go anywhere!
- Yes it's always summer in Shire, but the road goes through winter. Onwards, Frodo!
- Onwards it is then…
Here's how the long travel from Shire to Mordor started.
The raindrops sang their song, then first snowflake came.
The Gandalf's prophecy came true: the winter has come.
The song was merry some time and sad another time.
You know, when you're wet and your baggage weight tripled, and then frost bites, the thoughts aren't so merry.
…and then one day they heard the sound hooves knocking!
It came from afar, they couldn't see the source, but understood it's a danger.
- Hey! Someone's riding! Boys!
- Come here, everyone!
- We need to hide behind a hill!
- Why should we hide?
- Quiet! Hide, everyone, quickly!
- We need to be very cautious!
- Oh Frodo, what a horror.
- Poor us! When we have a chance for a breakfast, lunch and a dinner?
- I'm hungry indeed!
- Our road goes to the Buckland, to the old Maggot's tavern. Maggot will help us!
- Let's go, boys!
- Here you are! What do you want?
- We need some warmth and food!
- The tavern is opened to everyone!
Eat and drink, just pay the money!
- Thank you, the beer is delicious! And the pastries are exceptional.
- Do you like it? All right, spill it out, who are you?
Actually, I know that myself. Who in the Shire doesn't know Frodo Baggins and his good fellows?
- Mister, I'm not Frodo Baggins. My name is Underhill.
- Why would you change the name? But I've a guess
- What could you guess? Our travel is a secret. We only need to get to the ferry…
- Gotcha! I must warn you! Although maybe you don't need it…
- We need it! Master! Speak!
- Three days ago I heard my dogs barking furiously. There was a scary rider knocking on my gate.
- What a horror!
- All clad in black, on black horse.
- What was next?
- He kept asking if I know where Frodo from the Bag End and the three friends of him had gone. "Tell me where, I'll bring you gold!"
… he was so scary: hissed, growled,  bowed to the ground, as if he wasn't alive…
- And what did you say?
- And I was all like: Get out of here, bring your gold to someone else, I know nothing!
- Quiet, quiet! So, you don't need gold, but keep asking money from us, eh?
- Of course, you gotta pay for the drinks, but for betrayal… I don't need money for betrayal, I'm an honest person!
My life isn't easy but I never betrayed anyone!
But about you — I know something. The folks are talking!
- What?
- You're good lads! Never did evil to anyone! Go back home, live quietly!…
- You see, we never did evil. My word! And will never do to anyone.
But I have to ask for a favor: help us to get to the river ferry. Be a lad!
- Do you have coin for that? Ah, just kidding!
I'll ask my brothers to bring you there safely.
Hurry up! The night is coming.
- My dear, my good Hobbits! I thought it well, and I decided: our travel is vey dangerous.
It's nothing like a quest for a treasure, not a "trip there and back again".
The death awaits at every corner!
- Ah, Frodo, like we'd never guessed! We only follow this Ring because we know how dangerous the road is.
We go to help you!
- "The Ring"? You said "the Ring", Merry? How do you know?
- Did you think we don't know? I knew about the Ring for like, 100 years. Bilbo himself told me.
You wanted to be secretive, so I didn't chatter…
- I know about the Ring too. By accident…
-… And so when Gandalf asked us to help you, we said nothing against!
- Remember, he told you: "Take those you can trust".
- Who can I trust now? With friends like this…
- We'll go into fire, and water, and snow for you!
- We won't abandon you, don't even think about it! We're your friends!
- Thanks, friends!
- Frodo, we follow you with full understanding, don't worry!
The road went uphill. Tree branches were getting denser and darker. The silence was eerie.
But Hobbits felt like they were being watched by cold, suspicious, hostile eyes.
- Where's the winter?
- It probably ended… or suspended
- Ouch, friends! Looks like we're in the Old Forest.
- They tell scary stories about unholy things here…
- Enough, Pippin, I don't believe int this fairytales… but they say the trees in this forest don't like strangers… and they watch…watch with all their…
- Leaves? They don't have eyes, don't they?
- Got scared?
- A bit…
- And you, Brandybuck?
- No, and you?
- And Pippin got scared!
- Anyway, we had to go through the Old Forest. There's no other road. No way to avoid the Old Forest.
- Let me throught! Let me through! I plan no malice!
- Quiet, don't cry! It won't help. We're going to die together…
- We won't die, where did you get that? Neither together nor by ourselves.
- I feel drowsy… I'm falling asleep…
- Frodo, don't sleep!
- Why?
- It's not a mere sleep!
- It's a sleep!
- It's some kind of sorcery!
- No, Brandybuck…
- I'm falling asleep too…
- I'm falling asleep too…I'm falling asleep too…
- It's me, eternal Old Man Willow, casting an eternal sleep on you!
Enjoy it! Let all your troubles go.
…Your bodies will weaken, and you'll be a food for the trees of the Old Forest!
Stay here! Eternal sleep! This is what every conscientious person should strive for!
- Whose are these feet? Ah, Brandybuck! Merry! What happened to you?
Pippin! Sam! Wake up, lads, we're in trouble!
- What happened?
- Brandybuck got caught! The Willow swallowed him! Help me!
- Ah you, unholy thing! Wait a bit, I'll bring some fire and we'll burn its skin. Maybe then it'll let our Merry go!
- Sam, help me! Merry, do you hear us?
- Here, let me put fire on it. Here, get it! How are you, Merry?
- Stop it! Stop it! Or this thing will cut me in half!
- Remove the fire!… Quiet! I here a song!
A song! The help is near! Boys, follow me!
- Whoa! Whoa! steady there! Now, my little fellows,
Where be you a-going to, puffing like a bellows?
What's the matter here then?
Do you know who I am?
I'm Tom Bombadil!
Tell me what's your trouble!`
- Sir! My friend is caught in the willow-tree!
- What? Old Man Willow? Naught worse than that, eh? That can soon be mended. I know the tune for him.
You let him out again, Old Man Willow! What be you a-thinking of? You shouldn't be waking!
Eat earth, Dig deep! Drink water! Bombadil is talking!
- One! Two! Three!
- Thank you sir!
- You shall come home with me! The table is laden with yellow cream, honeycomb, and white bread and butter. Golderry is waiting.
- He speaks in poems!
- Who's this Goldberry?
- Maybe his wife?
- Time enough for questions around the supper table.
You follow after me a quick as you are able!
- Don't worry, dear friends. No danger will find you here. Leave the damp night in the forest!
Maybe you're still afraid of the fogs, dark trees, swamps and sloughs? Forget it! No fears! Now you're safe with Tom Bombadil!
- Here's my pretty lady! Here's my Goldberry clothed all in silver-green with flowers in her girdle!
Is the table laden? I see yellow cream and honeycomb, and white bread, and butter,
milk, cheese and green herbs and ripe berries gathered. Is that enough for us? Is the supper ready?
- Let's eat, lads!
- Wash yourself first! Warm clean water is the best way to leave the fears behind!
- Now it's time for the supper.
- Eat boys, eat!
- Time to sleep. The night will fly quickly, and you'll be ready to continue your travel.
- Sleep… Sleep… Sleep…
- Who are you, the giant? Tell me!
- Don't you know my name, Tom? That's the only answer.
- And I am Frodo!
- Restore your strength and fear nothing. I know everything about you, no need to tell. I'm glad I can help you on your long path.
- Thank you!
- Show me your magic ring.
- The Ring? Well, I can even give it up to you…
- No, no, just show it to me.
- Here, take it from me, it's scary…
- There're forces stronger than this Ring. The force of fearlessness and love for life will damage it… But only you can destroy it once and for all.
- We?
- Yes. Take it back.
Tomorrow, new trials await you. Be prepared for everything. Go the western slope of the Downs, besides the Barrows.
…If you're lucky, you'll strike the Great Road in a day's journey.
- …The Great Road…
- Listen carefully and remember:
Ho! Tom Bombadil, Tom Bombadillo!
By water, wood and hill, by the reed and willow,
By fire, sun and moon, harken now and hear us!
Come, Tom Bombadil, for our need is near us!
- This is in case you're in trouble.
- …in case we're in trouble…
- Now sleep!
- Good night!
- Frodo, my friend! Now you're safe with your friends. But remember, this is just a respite.
New dangers await for you. The winter will return.
- Wake up, friends! Get up!
Speed now! And hold to your purpose!
North with the wind in the left eye and a blessing on your footsteps.
Farewell! Happy travels!
- Looks like I'm lost.
Merry! Sam! Pippin! Where're you, boys?
- FRODO! FRODO!
- Lord, I'm scared!
END OF PART 1