THE KEEPERS (Fellowship)
A fantasy based on the novel by JRR Tolkien
Part 2
- Looks like I'm lost.
Merry! Sam! Pippin! Where're you, boys?
- FRODO! FRODO!
- Lord, I'm scared!
- We're here! Frodo!
- Boys! Somebody, help!
- I am the Barrow-Wight! Horrible and cold!
Do you see my eyes? They'll chain your heart with frost!
Why hurry? Soon will come the end to everything, joys and troubles!
You'll stay here, underground. You'll be clad in wonderful clothes!
The gold will surround you!
Look. look how much of it is here under the ground!
Gold, gold, treasures are everywhere!
The are cold! They only glitter under sun
…but underground they are dead! DEAD!
They are plenty, and they'll be yours!
Stay here! You may be dead, but you are fabulously rich! Rich! RICH!
- Maybe I should put on the magic Ring?
Then, invisible, at the dawn I'll be able to run through the grass covered in dew…
…alive and safe myself, but lamenting my friends — Sam,  Merry, Pippin?
No! No-no! Hobbits don't abandon friends in trouble! No!
- Merry! Do you hear me, Merry?
- Ouch, how cold is your face!
- Sam…You're so cold too!
- Pippin? You look like dead, all of you!
- Why do you lie here like the dead in the barrow?
Who threw the jewels on you?
Why are you silent?
- Pippin! Sam! Boys!
Boys! We shall never perish!
Remember, Tom told to call him if a trouble happens?
Ho! Tom Bombadil, Tom Bombadillo!
By water, wood and hill, by the reed and willow,
By fire, sun and moon, harken now and hear us!
Come, Tom Bombadil, for our need is near us!
- One moment, kids! I'll help you!
- Oh, lads! You got some trouble here! You need to be more careful!
- Yes, sir, thank you…
- Now take your ponies and go away!
- But…treasures… What about treasures?
- Don't touch the treasures, let's leave them here.
- Each of you will get a dagger, long and narrow. That will be your protection from the Dark Lord. Now, back to your travel!
Our heroes grew more fearless every minute.
Valiant Hobbits thought that most of their adventures are over.
But was far from being true
Soon they passed a rarely walked upon crossroads and reached the Barliman Butterbur's tavern.
In the tavern, a new meeting awaited them.
- Here's it - the "Prancing Pony" tavern.
- …"owned by Barliman…"
- Barliman Butterbur.
- Let's stop here for a rest!
- Let's do it!
- Ah, welcome, welcome, dear guests! Bring the supper!
Take your seats!
- Who are you, dear guests?
- We're from Shire!
- Ah, I know your folks! What're your names?
- My? I'm Underhill. And these are my friends: Pippin Took, Merry Brandybuck and Sam Gamgee.
- I now the latter three, but never heard about an Underhill from Shire. Maybe he has another name?
- Dear guests!… why do you bug the travellers? Let them rest!
- Mister! Mister! Here's my advice: better leave. The talk takes dangerous route.
- That's OK. I've nothing to hide!
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely! I want some fun myself! Do you, guys?
- Frodo, Frodo! Do we really need more troubles?
You must be in fever. You're so pale.
- I've no fever! I'm not pale! I've nothing to hide, I didn't stab or kill or rob anybody!
Let's have fun, friends!
…Now quicker the fiddle went deedle-dum-diddle;
the dog began to roar,
The cow and the horses stood on their heads;
The guests all bounded from their beds
and danced upon the floor.
With a ping and a pong the fiddle-strings broke!
the cow jumped over the Moon,
And the little dog laughed to see such fun,
And the Saturday dish went off at a run
with the silver Sunday spoon.
- Really, something wrong goes on…
- Now, mister, better stop playing with your toy.
You'll call trouble on yourself.
- And where do you know me from?
- I know because I'm waiting here for you. I'm waiting for Frodo Baggins.
- But I am Underhill.
- Well, as you wish.
- Frodo, let's go to sleep. Stop attracting attention to us.
- Let's go.
- Ah, I'm really tired… But I want to mingle so much. I miss parties so much.
- I feel bad for you: you're too tired, lost the rest of your brains…
- How can one lose their brains? If only along with head…
- Oh, it's quite possible!
- OK, OK, we need to lay down, to hide. But you two are like "brains, brains"…
- So, you are in fact mister Frodo Baggins?
- I am Underhill.
- My friend Gandalf described you to me and told you'll be calling yourself "Underhill".
You're in danger!
- See, Frodo, see, we're in danger!
- Quiet, Sam! So, Gandalf is your friend? I really lost my mind.
…But this means nothing.
- Three days ago, the Black Riders were here.
- They were at my throat: "give me Frodo Baggins!" - but where I could get one?
And now you're here.
- Frodo, you need to be careful.
- What are you trying to say?
-  That you need to save yourself, instead of fooling around! Here's a letter for you from Gandalf.
- Letter from Gandalf!
- Come on, read it and go to sleep. You're so bewildered.
- I beg you - save yourselves, and I'll help you in that.
- Who are you? And why would we need your help?
- It's not that common to meet a person who offers a hand on a hard path like yours.
- Will you read that letter already?
- Come on, read it!
- "My friend Frodo, leave the Bag End as soon as possible. Run from Shire. The Black Riders hunt you.…
…You can trust Barliman the tavernkeeper.…
…On your road you'll meet a friend known as the Strider. He knows everything and will help.
Hurry up and forgive me…
…Don't put the Ring on at any cost. Travel by day, hide by night.…
… P.S.: the real name of the Strider is Aragorn…
…All that is gold does not glitter,
Not all those who wander are lost;
The old that is strong does not wither,
Deep roots are not reached by the frost.
From the ashes a fire shall be woken,
A light from the shadows shall spring;
Renewed shall be blade that was broken,
The crownless again shall be king."
- "G" for Gandalf!
- Gandalf!
- Dear mister Strider! I'm going to test you.
What's your real name? Come on, spit it out!
- I'm Aragorn!
- Aragorn…
- I'm the real Strider and Gandalf's friend.
- He looks like a good man!
- …And if by life or death I can save you, I will!
You are tired. but we got to go.
- Gentlemen! I was just told: they're here!
- Who?
- The Black Riders!
- Save ourselves!
- Don't panic! We'll deceive them for now… and I'm afraid to think, what's next.
- Let's go, guys!
- Afraid to think? But we need to go. Frodo?
- A decoy first!
- Let's go!
- Godspeed!
- Thank you, dear mister Butterbur!
- Frodo, hurry up!
The road to Rivendell was long and hard.
Many times the travelers met the signs left by Gandalf - so he must have been there before them.
And then it happened, the scariest things: ominous shadows started moving to them from all directions!
…Those were the shadows of the Black Riders!
- I'm so scared… I want to put the ring on and become invisible so badly!
- No, no, Go away! Go back to the Land of Mordor! I won't give up!
- Yes! Come here! You're ours! You belong to Mordor!
- Begone! Begone!
- The Ring! Give us the Ring!
- I swear, you'll never get the Ring! I'm not yours! I won't give up!
- What time is it? What happened to me? Is it summer or winter again?
What's wrong with me?
- You're in the castle of the lord of Rivendell, Elrond.
- Gandalf? Am I dreaming?
- I'm here, dear friend, here. Forgive me for not accompanying you on your path.
You'll learn the reasons later.
Are you in pain?
- No… just my arm…
- You were wounded with a poisoned sword of a Black Rider.
- I'm so happy, Gandalf, because it's all over, and I don't have to go anywhere…
- No, Frodo, it's all ahead of us.
Forgive me, friend, but you passed only a half of the road.
- Mister Frodo!
- Sam! Dear friend! I'm so glad!…
- I told you, I told you. Oh, your poor hand, Frodo! It's so cold and almost transparent… Just look at it!
- Come on, it's warm!
- Yes, a warm hand… Get up, I'll help you. Be careful! let's go to the patio! There's a surprise for you there!
- I love surprises! Let's go!
- Here's my surprise! Do you see them, Frodo?
- Merry!
- Frodo!
- We're in the Elrond's castle too!
- I'm so happy… *ouch* I'm so glad to see you again my friends!
- Be afraid of nothing, Frodo! Of course, nobody wants new troubles, but there's no progress without them!
- Frodo, we'll take more rations this time, so we'll want nothing!
I'll be turned into a horse by the power of Frodo, the Lord of the Ring!
- You're wrong, Pippin! The Lord of the Ring is evil black Sauron, we are just its Keepers.
- No, friends, I've made my mind: I'll not go any further; I'll return back to the Bag End.
I'm so afraid, I'm wounded, my arm hurts…
- Frodo! Don't be afraid, we all will go with you!
- No, friends! Why me? Why I had to pass all these ordeals? I won't go anywhere!
- And now they wait for us in the Hall of Fire. We'll make a decision there.
- Hurry up, Frodo.
- No, Gandalf…
- Hurry up! There's a surprise for you!
- A surprise?
- Yes, yet another one.
- All right, we shall see…
- And you, friends, prepare! Prepare to a long travel!
…I'm not afraid of Gollum…
…He used to be a mortal…
…Now he's a swamp monster…
…Who's ruined by the magic ring…
- Frodo!
- Bilbo!
- What happened to you?
- I was wounded in my shoulder, BIlbo…
- How come?
- You know, 4 Black Riders suddenly surrounded me…
- …one Rider struck me with his sword, and I remember nothing more. I only woke up in this wonderful land.
- What about the Ring, Frodo? You…didin't…
- No, I didn't give them the Ring!
- Good, Frodo! I'm so happy to see you!
- And I'm happy too! I swear, I thought I'll never see you again…
- Frodo… As if Bilbo Baggins could disappear!
- No, you couldn't!
- The duty brought me to meet you, Frodo!
- The Hall of Fire is the best place for our council.
The magic of fire is eternal. It bring us warmth and light.
We all gathered here to avoid a disaster, to prevent the Darkness from engulfing the whole of Middle-Earth:
Gandalf…
Aragorn the Strider…
Knight Boromir, an envoy from the Men of the South…
You, Bilbo Baggins…
You, dear Hobbits…
And Dwarves the laborers…
And Legolas the Elf.
- We must decide, who will continue the path to the Land of the Dark Lord, Mordor, to destroy the Ring of Power.
Show it to us, Frodo!
- Frodo, show it to us!
- I missed it so much, Frodo…
- Beware, Bilbo, the Ring of Power kills the soul.
- But…But it calls for me…
Give it to me! Give it!
- …It's over. The pain goes away. Now you understand why I gave it to Frodo.
I got to used to it. And it started twisting me.
- I'm am envoy from the Men of the South.
The Ring of Powers, I heard, had vanished without a trace… but it is back on the Earth now!
A shiny little ring…
(…it pulls me… it pulls me…a shiny little ring…it pulls me… IT PULLS ME…)
- You have no other way than fighting the Enemy to death, even without a hope for victory.
And the Ring… The very reason we assembled here is deciding what to do with the Ring.
- If the Ring needs to be destroyed, there's no need for the Keeper to go into Mordor.
…but if we need to destroy the Enemy, it's stupid to reject the…military… help.
- If it happened so that we hold the Ring now, it must be destroyed in the very place it was forged: in the Mordor, at the Flaming Mountain!
- Friends! We talk a lot!
- We're looking for the truth!
- That can be done much faster!
- Gandalf the Gray! You seem to order us. Are we not smart enough for you?
- While the Ring of Power is here, we'll be fighting each other!
- Gandalf, better tell us, where were you all the time we were going from Shire to this hospitable castle.
- I was…in a very hospitable place… almost lost my head there.
- Gandalf, could that be because of the Ring, too?
- Yes, because of it.
- I went to the castle Isengard, to the White wizard Saruman.
- Hail, Saruman, the White wizard!
- Welcome, Gandalf the Gray!
- I came for your help.
- You? You're wizard too. Why do you need my help?
- We need to unite against the Dark Lord Sauron who threatens the peaceful Shire.
- Is it the Ring of Power that you're talking about?
- Yes, yes, that's it. It needs to be destroyed promptly, for it brings evil…
- Don't waste words. We the wizards know the value of empty words.
- Why do you see my words as empty?
- Not all of them. For we indeed should unite. But we need to unite to make the Ring of Power ours!
- A new force emerged on the Earth. The time of Elves is over.
Ancient alliances are powerless in the face of this force.
We need to support it. Its victory is nigh. And those who support it will be rewarded.
The Wise ones, like you and me, will learn to control this force.
But at first we'll be denouncing its harsh methods, while, secretly, supporting its goals:
…Wisdom, prosperity, order!
We'll be very wealthy!
- Many times I heard speeches like this - from our enemies, the Dark Lord's followers!
I'm leaving!
- You know where the Ring is. Tell me! Tell!
- No! Now that I know your intents I'll tell nothing.
- Then you'll stay here until you speak!
- And how did you escape, Gandalf?
- The strongest of the mountain eagles, Gwaihir the Windlord, helped me.
…He rescued me. But this is why I was delayed. It's not my fault that I was late with helping you, Frodo.
- Saruman turned out to be a traitor.
- Let's make the Ring of Power our weapon, if it conceals such a tremendous force!
- The forces of Light can't use it. It only serves black deeds. We must destroy it!
- Only Frodo can do it.
- No! No way! I'm a simple peaceful Hobbit. Meeting the evil only disturb me and make me weak. I'm afraid of pain and betrayal, Gandalf.
- And still it's you, Frodo, who will do it. Because a weak one can do it better than a strong one.
You see, a strong one isn't used to avoid danger and dies fighting, but it's the weak ones who often transformed the world
when the strong ones were powerless.
- Gentlemen! I'm ready to go! I started the whole story with the accursed Ring, and I'm ready to go.
- Stop it, Bilbo, stop it. You'll meet the braves when they're back.
…And remember: even in the evil Sauron's realm you'll find friends.
Those who join you are myself…
…Strider, …
… Gimli, son of the Gloin the Dwarf…
…Legolas the Elf…
…and Boromir, the envoy of the Men of the South.
Nine in total, like the Black Riders who are nine too
- Friends, any proposals?
- Frodo, I propose going back!
- The only ways we can return is with victory or with defeat!
- with shame?
- or with shame!
- No!
- I propose going forward!
- I support that. If we turn back, the Enemy will attack Rivendell, and the Shadow will enclose the Middle-Earth.
- My friends, Gandalf the Gray is right. We need to go forward. Let's go, guys!
- *sigh* Forward…
- Hey, peckers up, guys!
- How can one drop a pecker? If only lying face down?
- Mister Frodo! Do you hear it?
- Danger! We're pursued by Werewolves!
- Friends, the cave Karadhras is ahead. Nobody will find us there!
- The cave Karadhras is ahead. Nobody will find us there!
- Forward, Shire!
- Hold on, Frodo! So much hassle with you… You're like a little baby! Could you watch your steps?
Always have your head in clouds… AAAAAH!
- Pippin! Hold on! Take my hand!
- Give your hand!
- Go, go, don't fall behind! Here's a shortcut! Don't fall behind!
- Come on, guys!
- Well, friends, we're safe now!
- We're in the land of Moria.
- What kind of land is this Moria?
- Dwarves, the little laborers, used to live here.
- Dear friends, let's eat something. I doubt we'll find chairs in Moria, but we can east seating on these steps.
Pippin, distribute the rations.
- And where had those Dwarves gone, the masters of this land?
- Evil Orcs attacked them and sacked their realm.
- Orcs, horror! You hear, Gandalf, Orcs!
- Quieter. Don't scare everyone.
- Orcs! We're trapped!
- Strike, the Shire!
- Retreat! Retreat!
- Merry! Are you alive? Merry?
- As far as I know, the dead don't talk.
- Onwards!
- Careful!
- Quiet!
- Walk the bridge without fear - you can see it's safe. Follow me!
- Go, go!
- Onwards!
- Careful!
- Quiet!
- We're safe! Let's do a head count!
…One…two…three…five…But where's Gandalf? Who saw him last? Frodo?
…Could he stay in the cave? I'm afraid he perished defending us. Ah, Gandalf, Gandalf…
- We are orphaned. It's all over.
- Nothing is over. The Golden Forest awaits us.
- But how shall we tell it's the Golden Forest?
- The imagination is a great power!
- Especially when you're hungry.
- Look, look! Everything ahead is as if it was covered with mist!
Look, look!
- Welcome to the magic forest of Elves! You're now our guests!
- We're pursued by Orcs! We don't want to bring you problems!
- Don't be afraid. The time has stopped here. You'll restore here. The forest aromas will replenish you. The time has stopped here.
- The unknown troubles on hidden trails might be more dangerous than open enemies on mountain roads!
- We're not enemies and bear no danger to you!
- They all fell asleep!
- We need to awake them!
- No need. They need rest.
# Nothing here
- Tired Keepers lied on the grass. But stunned Frodo was looking around.
He saw a long-vanished world, illuminated by the light long-disappeared,
and that incredibly ancient world was opening to his amazed eyes as if it was just being born.
He only saw colors he knew: white, yellow, green, blue
But they were so fresh and bright, as if he saw them for the first time.
While here, one couldn't miss winter in summer, or dream of summer in winter.
In the unchanging realm of Elves the past and future were one.
…But Gandalf wasn't with them.
- No, we need to awake them!
- Awake! Friends, we need to move on!
- How entangled is everything in this world! Winter, spring… You don't know what are you dreaming about…
- But we can't dream for too long. Any dream is only beautiful if it can be fulfilled!
Onward to the Forest Keep!
- Frodo, come here!
- Frodo, it's time! Here's the Forest Keep!
- Where's Legolas? Legolas, don't fall back!
- Noble Keepers! I know you bear the ominous Ring of Power.
- And you're devoted to destroying it.
You're going the hard path, full of danger and sorrows.
- …and of hunger!
- You want to stop the Evil. But this is impossible!
-Why?
- I am Galadriel the Seeress and I tell you: the Evil always creates Evil.
You want to stop it but it's inevitable.
The Evil is the Black star; the White star shining next to it - that is the Good.
What will you compare the splendor of the White star, if not with the Black star?
The Evil is inevitable!
- I don't think so. I think everyone who can provide a help in a trouble, must do it.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
- Galadriel! You're wise, fearless and fair. Do you want me to give the Ring to you?
- To me?
- Yes. It's power is too much for me - and you will help us.
- Keeper, I won't deny that:
I often think, what will I do if the magic Ring of Power falls into my hands.
And now I can get it…
- Yes, certainly.
- You will save us!
- No, I passed the test. I won't take your Ring. I'll stay myself, as I am know.
But I want to help you and to warn you:
Look into this magic chalice - but don't touch the water!
- It's me, Sauron, the Dark Lord! I watch you! Give the Ring to me, Frodo!
Drop it into the chalice! It won't help you anyway!
- You have two roads: one goes back to the Shire, another one goes to Mordor. What road will you choose?
- We have only one road. Only forward, only to Mordor.
- I worried about you, Frodo. If the Orcs are near, it's too dangerous to wander the garden alone.
…Especially to you - you're the truly precious prize for the enemies now!
- Thank you!
- Please allow me to sit here with you - given I found you.
- The Ring… The Ring… Such a small trinket, a little ring brings so many troubles to us.
Well, show it to me. For I haven't  seen it well enough during the Elrond's council.
- It's better to keep it concealed.
- Don't repeat others' words, Frodo! You said yourself you'd like to get rid of it…
So give it to me!
The Ring will give me great power!
Valiant knights of all the free lands will flock to my banners!
And, with the Ring's help, we'll be able to crush the Enemy's host!
Do I look like a traitor?
Yes, I need your Ring…
But, by my honor, I'll give it back to you
…After the victory.
- Fool! Obstinate fool! It is by our own folly you'll perish, and you'll ruin all of us!
It is not yours save by unhappy chance. It might have been mine. It should be mine. Give it to me!
- Boromir! Is it really you?
No. I can't trust the Ring to anyone. Farewell!
- Frodo, come back! Come ba…
- Where're you going, Frodo? What about the others?
- You see, Sam, I must go alone. I feel the dark power of the Ring is acting already in the Fellowship.
Everyone is so tired. I must go alone.
- How come, Frodo? How come? Without everyone? Without me?
What if anything happens to you?
Who'll rescue you? Who'll make a fire to warm you? Who'll feed you, Frodo?
No, I can't tolerate that, do you hear me? Frodo?
- Ahh, seems I failed to leave on my own.
You know, Sam - I'm extremely glad. It is plain that we were meant to go together till the very end.
- Frodo! You know, the winter is back behind the gate. I beg you - put on your warm coat
All right! I'll certainly do!
But you  know, Sam, in our travels I got used to the winter road and frost.
And if we're cold - we'll make a fire, really!
- And we'll get warm!
- And we'll get warm, Sam! Onwards, lad!